Gerald R. Gill Papers MS170
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Teaching materials, 1978 -- 2007; MS170.007; 24 Linear Feet 20 record cartons
  - Student papers and review copies, 1974 -- 2007; MS170.007.003; 11 Linear Feet 11 record cartons
    - Tufts theses, dissertations, and senior special projects, 1974 -- 2007; MS170.007.003.002; 6 Linear Feet 5 full record cartons, 2 partial record cartons, 2 legal-sized folders
      - "Girls with Guns: Gender and Political Violence," Sandy Martin, 1993; MS170.007.003.002.038.00029; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 29)
      - "Gun Buy-Backs: Gun Control for the 1990s," Kathleen McGilvray, 1994; MS170.007.003.002.038.00030; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 30)
      - "Haitian American Women at Tufts," Charlene Desir, circa 1995; MS170.007.003.002.038.00031; 1 Folder(s) (Box 38, Folder 31)
      - "Harris Wofford: Passion to Serve," David Lieberman, 2005; MS170.007.003.002.039.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - "Hidden Faces: U.S. Women Vietnam Veterans and their Struggle for Respect and Reason In and After Vietnam," Ilyse Lerner, 2000; MS170.007.003.002.039.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - "Historical Analysis and Recommendations for Nubian Roots Youth Committee and DSNI for Rebuilding the Dudley Community," Bayyinah J. Morton, 1994; MS170.007.003.002.039.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - "Historical Analysis of the U.S.'s policies for Dependent Children and their Families," Cherilyn E. Davidson, 1989; MS170.007.003.002.039.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - "A History of the Student South African Divestment Campaign at Tufts University, 1977--1989," John Dizgun, 1994; MS170.007.003.002.039.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 5)
      - "'History Recorded, History Revealed': African Americans, Tobacco, and Deceit," Valerie Janelle Rock, 2003; MS170.007.003.002.039.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 6)
      - "HIV/AIDS and Incarcerated Black Women," Sydney Lauren McKinney, 2005; MS170.007.003.002.039.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 7)
      - "Howard University: 'Capstone of Negro Education in World War II," Gregory Hunter, 1991; MS170.007.003.002.039.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 8)
      - "How the Civil Rights Movement Displayed the Power of the Media in Connecting People and Shaping Public Opinion," Biodun Kajopaye, circa 2005; MS170.007.003.002.039.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 9)
      - "I Could Remember A Time I Thought The World Was Mine…" Marisol Rodriguez, 2006; MS170.007.003.002.039.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 10)
      - "'I Feel So Anxious to Learn': The Role of African Americans in Virginia's Educational Reconstruction, 1865--1877," Hillary Green, 2003; MS170.007.003.002.039.00011; 2 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 11-12)
      - "'If Not By Race, Then By What?': A Critical Analysis of the Elimination of Race-Based Programs in Higher Education" thesis proposal, Nytangia Leitzey, 2004; MS170.007.003.002.039.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 13)
      - "Images of Black People in Late Medieval and Early Modern Japan," Gary P. Leupp, circa 1980; MS170.007.003.002.039.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 14)
      - "In Defense of the Districts," Emily Goldberg, circa 1995; MS170.007.003.002.039.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 15)
      - "Indian Birth Control Advocates in the Early Twentieth Century," Michele Malter, circa 2005; MS170.007.003.002.039.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 16)
      - "In Search of History and Voice: Black Women's Life Narratives of Twentieth Century South Africa," Nana Danquaah Osafo, circa 1999; MS170.007.003.002.039.00016; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 17)
      - "In Search of History and Voice: Black Women's Life Narratives of Twentieth Century South Africa," Nana Danquaah Osafo, circa 1999; MS170.007.003.002.039.00017; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 18)
      - "Israel's Dangerous Imagination: Dimona and the Kennedy Administration," Zachary S. Kahn, 2000; MS170.007.003.002.039.00018; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 19)
      - "I Wannabe Like You: Race, Assimilation and Miscegenation in Disney's The Little Mermaid and Pocahontas," S. E. King, 2000; MS170.007.003.002.039.00019; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 20)
      - "Jazz," Gregg Kallor, 2000; MS170.007.003.002.001.00036; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 37)
      - "The Jews of New Orleans, 1730--1860", circa 1995; MS170.007.003.002.039.00020; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 21)
      - Jones, Lucille thesis proposal, 2005; MS170.007.003.002.039.00021; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 22)
      - "Journeys in My Skin: Poems of Self-Discovery," Natasha Mann, circa 2001; MS170.007.003.002.039.00022; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 23)
      - "Korean-Black Relations: the Effect of Korean Immigration on Blacks in New York City and Los Angeles," Christopher Chung, 1995; MS170.007.003.002.039.00023; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 24)
      - "Labor, Empire and Indians in Trinidad," Sunil Purushotham, 2005; MS170.007.003.002.039.00024; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 25)
      - "The Lasting Legacy of Little Rock," Mary Ann Anderson, 2003; MS170.007.003.002.039.00025; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 26)
      - Latin@s at Tufts University papers, 2004; MS170.007.003.002.039.00026; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 27)
      - "Law, Politics, and Slavery in the Massachusetts Bay Colony, 1686--1738," James J. Allegro, 1997; MS170.007.003.002.039.00027; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 28)
      - "LBJ, Israel, and the Crisis in the Middle East," James Howard Post, 1993; MS170.007.003.002.039.00028; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 29)
      - "The Left and the Strategy and Tactics of American Labor: Flint 1936--1937 and Beyond," Daniel DiMaggio, 2007; MS170.007.003.002.039.00029; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 30)
      - "Let Conscience Be My Guide Part II: An Oral History of Conscientious Objectors in the Vietnam War," Mark Anstendig, 1989; MS170.007.003.002.039.00030; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 31)
      - "The Limits of Postwar Liberalism: The National Urban League, The Congress of Industrial Organizations, and African American Women Workers," Jill Clark, 2002; MS170.007.003.002.039.00031; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 32)
      - "Little, Yellow, Different, and Interned, to the Contrary: Active, Assertive, Involved," Sherry Dong, 1995; MS170.007.003.002.039.00032; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 33)
      - Locke, Caroline project proposal on white musicians performing Black music, 1999; MS170.007.003.002.039.00033; 1 Folder(s) (Box 39, Folder 34)
      - Manuscript on "colored regiments" in the Civil War, circa 2000; MS170.007.003.002.040.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 1)
      - "Mary McLeod Bethune," Tamara E. Robinson, 1992; MS170.007.003.002.040.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 2)
      - "Masculinity in Sports," Adam Delany-Winn, circa 2005; MS170.007.003.002.040.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 3)
      - "The Mobilization of Newark, New Jersey Towards the 1970 Mayoral Election of Kenneth Gibson," Mindy Jaffe, 1996; MS170.007.003.002.040.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 4)
      - "My Journey: An African American History of Winston-Salem, North Carolina in the Twentieth Century," Rachael Susan Fulp, 1993; MS170.007.003.002.040.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 5)
      - "The Myths and Realities of Black-Jewish Relations: Black-Jewish Relation in New York and Atlanta, 1960--1973: A Comparative Study," Michael Yudell, 1992; MS170.007.003.002.040.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 6)
      - "A Nation Turns Its Lonely Eyes to You: The Transformation of the American Baseball Hero," Alex Kaplan, 1999; MS170.007.003.002.040.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 7)
      - "Negotiating Survival: Farmwomen's Participation In and Resistance To the Commercial Transformation of Midwestern Family Farms," Thea Lavin, 2001; MS170.007.003.002.040.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 8)
      - "'A New Day is Here': The Borden Case and Civil Rights Activism in Boston, 1932--1935" Eben Simmons Miller, 1998; MS170.007.003.002.040.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 9)
      - "New Urban Environmentalists: The Greening of Boston Community Organizations," Gina L. Coplon, 1996; MS170.007.003.002.040.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 10)
      - "'New Views Appear to be True': The Republican Press and the Confiscation Act of 1861," Edward J. Hutchinson, 2000; MS170.007.003.002.040.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 11)
      - "Off of Our Knees: The Black Panther Party, American Indian Movement, and the Young Lords Party's Call for Self-Determination," Jose M. DeJesus, 2003; MS170.007.003.002.040.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 12)
      - "Perceptions and Realities: Asian Americans, African Americans, and Proposition 209," Thea Marston, 1998; MS170.007.003.002.040.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 13)
      - "The Politics of Death: A Study of Political Symbolism in the American Capital Punishment Debate," Allison Michelle Lee, 1992; MS170.007.003.002.040.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 14)
      - "Popular Culture in America, 1765--1835," Jacob Aaron Strasser, 1999; MS170.007.003.002.040.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 15)
      - "Popular Culture in America, 1765--1835," Jacob Aaron Strasser, 1999; MS170.007.003.002.040.00016; 1 Folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 16)
      - "Popular Nonviolent Protest in South Africa," Jeff Ganz, circa 1990; MS170.007.003.002.040.00017; 1 Folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 17)
      - "Primus King and Georgia's Democratic White Primary," Kimberly Mitchell, 2007; MS170.007.003.002.040.00018; 1 Folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 18)
      - "Quaker Activists in the Peace and Civil Rights Movements, 1955--1975," Thomas P. Johnson, 1990; MS170.007.003.002.040.00019; 1 Folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 19)
      - "Rap Music, Social Movements, and Sexual Politics," Sandra Hanna, 1992; MS170.007.003.002.040.00020; 1 Folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 20)
      - "Reaching Out, Moving In: An Exploration of the Lakota Ghost Dance," Kristaps Paddock, 2002; MS170.007.003.002.040.00021; 1 Folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 21)
      - "Recapturing the Role of Ideology in Social Movement Participation," David Moon, 2001; MS170.007.003.002.040.00022; 1 Folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 22)
      - "Recapturing the Role of Ideology in Social Movement Participation," David Moon, 2001; MS170.007.003.002.040.00023; 1 Folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 23)
      - "Reimag(in)ing the Rabbinate: An Oral History and Photo Essay of Women Rabbis," Bonnie Rosenbaum, 1995; MS170.007.003.002.040.00024; 1 Folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 24)
      - "Religious Leaders and their Impact on the Civil Rights Movement, 1955--1965," Rebecca A. Frank, 2005; MS170.007.003.002.040.00025; 2 Folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 25-26)
      - "The Republic of New Africa and the Quest for Land," John Moore, Jr., 1993; MS170.007.003.002.040.00026; 1 Folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 27)
      - "Returning Through the 'Door of No Return': A Case Study of African American Repatriation to Ghana," Seth M. Markle, 2000; MS170.007.003.002.040.00027; 1 Folder(s) (Box 40, Folder 28)
      - "Returning Through the 'Door of No Return': A Case Study of African American Repatriation to Ghana," Seth M. Markle, 2000; MS170.007.003.002.041.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - "Race, Faith, and Fascism: African American Religious and Secular Pacifism During World War II", circa 2000; MS170.007.003.002.041.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - "The Rise of the African American Left: John P. Davis and the National Negro Congress," Hilmar L. Jensen, 1997; MS170.007.003.002.041.00003; 2 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 3-4)
      - "The Role of Central Areas and Intimacy in Pompeian Domestic Space," Elizabeth Vickers, 2006; MS170.007.003.002.041.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 5)
      - "The Role of Christianity and Protestant Churches in the Korean American Community," James S. Kim, 1995; MS170.007.003.002.041.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 6)
      - Ruley, Tammi, honors thesis proposal, circa 2005; MS170.007.003.002.041.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 7)
      - "A Rural Battle on Segregation and a 40-Year War Within the Community," Julie Beglin, 1989; MS170.007.003.002.041.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 8)
      - "The Search for Direction: Southern Black Colleges and Universities After Segregation, 1954--1975," Carolyn Wilson, 2000; MS170.007.003.002.041.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 9)
      - "Separate and Unequal: Discrimination Against Working Women in Eastern Defense Industries During World War II," Samantha Longbaum, 1989; MS170.007.003.002.041.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 10)
      - Short stories, Leah Henderson, circa 2000; MS170.007.003.002.041.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 11)
      - "Slam Dunk: Basketball and the American Century", 2003; MS170.007.003.002.041.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 12)
      - "Sojourn in the City of Amalgamation: Race and Intermarriage in Boston, 1900--1930," Zebulon V. Miletsky, circa 2000; MS170.007.003.002.041.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 13)
      - "Something Special: The Relationship Between Commercial Black FM Radio and the African American Community in Washington, DC," Ginger Beverly, 1996; MS170.007.003.002.041.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 14)
      - "The South End Mosaic," Brent E. Wolfe, 1990; MS170.007.003.002.041.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 15)
      - "Speaking the Poem: The Role of the Oral Poet in Society, a Transatlantic Conversation," Jamila M. Moore, 2003; MS170.007.003.002.041.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 16)
        Contains related CD.
      - "Speaking the Poem: The Role of the Oral Poet in Society, a Transatlantic Conversation," Jamila M. Moore, 2003; MS170.007.003.002.041.00016; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 17)
      - "Staying Religious to Stay Sane: A Case Study on the Effect of Church Attendance on Depressive Symptomology in a Haitian American Community in Boston, Massachusetts," Barbara Ceptus, 2000; MS170.007.003.002.041.00017; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 18)
      - "Student Activism and the Civil Rights Movement at Tufts, 1955--1965," David N. Finkelman, 1987; MS170.007.003.002.041.00018; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 19)
      - "Student Activism and the Civil Rights Movement at Tufts, 1955--1965," David N. Finkelman, 1987; MS170.007.003.002.041.00019; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 20)
      - "Student Activism and the Civil Rights Movement at Tufts, 1955-1965," David N. Finkelman, 1987; MS170.007.003.002.001.00037; 1 Folder(s) (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - "Students Speak: School Choice in the Boston Pilot High Schools," Doyle, Feldman, Ouimette, Wagner, and Tung, 2003; MS170.007.003.002.041.00020; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 21)
      - Sue, Kimberly, family history, circa 2000; MS170.007.003.002.041.00021; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 22)
        75 years.
      - "Taking Over" play, Brad Hartz, 1989; MS170.007.003.002.041.00022; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 23)
      - "Theater as Protest: The Free Southern Theater in its Formative Years, 1963--1968," Sarah Marcus, 2002; MS170.007.003.002.041.00023; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 24)
      - Thesis on Jewish oral history, Liza Cohen, circa 1995; MS170.007.003.002.041.00024; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 25)
      - Thesis proposals, circa 2005; MS170.007.003.002.041.00025; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 26)
      - "Thugs, Thieves, and a Tiger: Tammany Hall, Richard Croker, and New York City During the Gay Nineties," Trevor Karpowich, 2003; MS170.007.003.002.041.00026; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 27)
      - "Title IX: An Analysis of Effective Efforts to Halt Sexual Discrimination," Whitney Anne Brusman, 1998; MS170.007.003.002.041.00027; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 28)
      - "To What Extent has the U.S. Equalized Educational Resources for its Youth?," Callie Sigal, 2007; MS170.007.003.002.041.00028; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 29)
      - "Tradition and Innovation: Food Imagery in Pop Art," Cambra Stern, 2000; MS170.007.003.002.041.00029; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 30)
      - "Tragedy on 16th Street: National Reaction to a Southern Horror," Laura E. Neidorf, circa 1995; MS170.007.003.002.041.00030; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 31)
      - "The Triumph of Spirit," Mitchell Pomerance, circa 1995; MS170.007.003.002.041.00031; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 32)
      - "The Tufts Campus During the World War II Years," Karen Kulvin, 1991; MS170.007.003.002.041.00032; 1 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 33)
      - "Tufts University and the Nature of the Student Movement in the Late 1960s and Early 1970s," Ellen Hessmer, 1981; MS170.007.003.002.041.00033; 2 Folder(s) (Box 41, Folder 34-35)
      - "Tufts University's Involvement in Boston Public School Desegregation," Amy Rutenberg, 1998; MS170.007.003.002.042.00001; 3 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 1-3)
      - "Turell Tufts: Identity in the U.S. Consul to Surinam in the Early Nineteenth Century," Barbara B. Strickland, 2006; MS170.007.003.002.042.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - "Turell Tufts: Identity in the U.S. Consul to Surinam in the Early Nineteenth Century," Barbara B. Strickland, 2006; MS170.007.003.002.042.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 5)
      - "Turell Tufts: Identity, Race, and Nationalism in the U.S. Consul to Surinam in the Early Nineteenth Century," Barbara B. Strickland, 2006; MS170.007.003.002.042.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 6)
      - "The UE: A Case Study of the Forces Influencing Union Development," Karen L. Smith, 1982; MS170.007.003.002.042.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 7)
      - "U.S. Intervention in Mexican Labor Relations, 1947--1960," Carlos Roy Aramayo, 1996; MS170.007.003.002.042.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 8)
      - "Unnatural Women, Unnatural Soldiers: Femininity, Military Service, and Women's Place in the WAC, WAVES, and WASP of World War II," Amy J. Rutenberg, 1999; MS170.007.003.002.042.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 9)
      - "Unnatural Women, Unnatural Soldiers: Femininity, Military Service, and Women's Place in the WAC, WAVES, and WASP of World War II," Amy J. Rutenberg, 1999; MS170.007.003.002.042.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 10)
      - Untitled paper on institutional racism, circa 1995; MS170.007.003.002.042.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 11)
      - Untitled paper on Louise Bennett and Alice Childress, Heather Simms, circa 1990; MS170.007.003.002.042.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 12)
      - Untitled paper on Louise Bennett and Alice Childress, Heather Simms, circa 1990; MS170.007.003.002.042.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 13)
      - Untitled thesis regarding African Americans and Islam in Boston, circa 2000; MS170.007.003.002.042.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 14)
      - "The Voice of Onyx: Black Students Speak Through Tufts Black Magazine of Literary and Visual Arts," Nakeila N. Pickrom, 2005; MS170.007.003.002.042.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 15)
      - "White Rap's Identity Crisis: The History of White Involvement in Hip Hop," Caroline Locke, 1999; MS170.007.003.002.042.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 16)
      - "A Woman Needs a Man Like a Fish Needs a Bicycle: Anglo-American Second Wave Feminism," Liz Grant, circa 2000; MS170.007.003.002.042.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 17)
      - "Women's Reproductive Decisions: Who's Really in Control?," Jennifer L. Tomasik, 1993; MS170.007.003.002.042.00016; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 18)
      - "Yale at War," Emilie MacRae, 2004; MS170.007.003.002.042.00017; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 19)
    - Grant proposals and review copies, 1995 -- 2006; MS170.007.003.003; .5 Linear Feet 1 partial record carton
      Grant proposals and review copies are arranged alphabetically by title.
      The grant proposals and review copies were materials related to Gill's interests that were sent to him by third parties for review.
      - Bellinger, Robert A. dissertation, 2002; MS170.007.003.003.042.00018; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 20)
      - "Blue Steel and Cinderblock: Poems from Prison," Detective J. Scott Hornoff, 2002; MS170.007.003.003.042.00019; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 21)
      - "Catholic Interracial Activity in Boston Before Busing," William C. Leonard, circa 2000; MS170.007.003.003.042.00020; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 22)
      - "Civil Rights in 1920s African American History," Mark R. Schneider, 2000; MS170.007.003.003.042.00021; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 23)
      - "Martin Luther King Jr., André Trocmé, and the Community of Nonviolence," Young Paik, 1999; MS170.007.003.003.042.00022; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 24)
      - O'Sullivan, Bryna, undergraduate research grant proposal, 2006; MS170.007.003.003.042.00023; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 25)
      - "Proposal for Interdisciplinary Doctorate Program at Tufts," Constantine Psimopoulos, 2006; MS170.007.003.003.042.00024; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 26)
      - "Taking Liberties: America's Cold War Against Labor," grant proposal, Sam Sills, 1995; MS170.007.003.003.042.00025; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 27)
      - "This Far by Faith," National Endowment for the Humanities grant proposal, 1998; MS170.007.003.003.042.00026; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 28)
      - Tufts University Campus Visit by President Lawrence Bacow, Cortland O. Dugger, 2004; MS170.007.003.003.042.00027; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 29)
      - "The U.S. Civil Rights Movement: Perspectives of the French Press and Black American Expatriates," Jessica M. Remick, 1997; MS170.007.003.003.042.00028; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 30)
      - "We Return Fighting: Civil Rights Movement in the Jazz Age," book proposal, Mark Schneider, circa 1995; MS170.007.003.003.042.00029; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 31)
      - "Within Our Gates: Human Sacrifice in the Landscape of the U.S.A.," grant proposal, Keith Morris Washington, 1999; MS170.007.003.003.042.00030; 1 Folder(s) (Box 42, Folder 32)
- University service, 1975 -- 2007; MS170.008; 3.6 Linear Feet 3 record cartons.
  University Service records document Gill's service to Tufts University as a member of university-level and departmental committees as well as his interests in larger Boston community projects. Materials consist of correspondence, manuals, memos, reports, agendas, notes, and minutes. This series documents Gill's strong commitment to issues related to affirmative action, race, the Tufts Black community, and the Tufts History Department.
  This series is arranged in three sub-series: University committees and service; Departmental committees and service; and Other service.
  - University committees and service, 1975 -- 2006; MS170.008.001; 1.2 Linear Feet 1 record carton.
    Sub-series is arranged chronologically, then alphabetically by subject.
    Sub-series includes reports and correspondence by the Task Force on Race, 1997-2001, the Tufts University Black Caucus, the Equal Educational Opportunity Committee, and the Society Organized Against Racism.
    This sub-series contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
    - Tufts University Black Caucus, 1975 -- 1991; MS170.008.001.043.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Tufts University Black Caucus, 1976 -- 1988; MS170.008.001.043.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Tufts University Black Caucus, 1981 -- 1982; MS170.008.001.043.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Black Faculty Caucus, 1995; MS170.008.001.043.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Black Faculty Caucus, 2002; MS170.008.001.043.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 43, Folder 5)
      20 years from date of creation.
    - Tufts University Black Caucus, 2004; MS170.008.001.043.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Equal Educational Opportunity Committee, 1983 -- 1986; MS170.008.001.043.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Equal Educational Opportunity Committee, 1988 -- 1989; MS170.008.001.043.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 43, Folder 8)